Finding aid for the Trans Archive Oral History Project CA.MS.01201
Smith College Archives
Trans Archive Oral History Project
2016-2017
Smith College Archives
Davis, Sam
CA.MS.01201
367 Gigabytes (162 digital files)
Content Description
Oral history interviews with Smith College students and alumnae who identify as trans and/or non-binary, conducted by Sam Davis (Class of 2017) for his documentary project entitled "In Our Own Words: On Being Trans at Smith." The interviews explore how these trans students fit into Smith's vision of "women for the world"; how are trans students supported or unsupported by the administration and their fellow students; and issues of erasure, hypervisibility, transphobia, views about trans students within all levels of the institution, and the ongoing debate of who does and does not "belong" at Smith.
Conditions Governing Access
Some oral histories in this collection have restrictions on access. Please see the notes attached to an individual interview for information about restrictions that apply to it.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Sam Davis donated the Trans Archive Oral History Project to the Smith College Archives in 2016.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
This collection contains materials received from the donor in digital form that are not currently available online. Please consult with Special Collections staff to request access to the digital files.
Electronic records; Oral histories; Transgender people--United States; Smith College -- Students -- History -- Sources; Anex-Ries, Quinn; Barker, Tucker; Barr, Sebastian; Christian-Solá, Gabriella; Collins-Sibley, Micah (Aba); Davis, Tobias; Devlin, Kai M.; Dunning, Robert; Foe, Parker; Lensing-Sharp, Dinah; Maisonet, Edsuvani; Montecalvo, Jess M.; Nonken, Erika; Novak, Ray; Owen, Izzy; Parker, Evelyn; Piňero, Marisa; Rasdall, Ryan; Rume, Taonga (Ty); Sherley, Cai; Shlasko, David; Strauss-Jenkins, Sophie; Velocci, Beans; Wetmore, Reed; Davis, Sam
- Video interview of Quinn Anex-Ries, 2016; 1 oral histories (1 mp4 and 7 mov video files)
  Conditions Governing Access
  This interview is open for use with following restrictions on access: the narrator has requested that this interview not be made available online. Please consult with Special Collections staff to request access to this digital content.
- Video interview of Tucker Barker, 2016; 1 oral histories (1 mp4 and 4 mov video files)
- Video interview of Sebastian Barr, 2016; 1 oral histories (1 mp4 and 5 mov video files)
  This interview is open for use without any restrictions.
- Text response of student W [pseudonym], 2016; 1 oral histories (1 digital text file)
  This interview is open for use with following restrictions on access: the narrator has requested that a pseudonym be used. A redacted version of the interview is available.
- Video interview of Gabriella Christian-Solá, 2016; 1 oral histories (1 mp4 and 6 mov video files)
  This interview is open for use without restrictions.
- Video interview of Micah (Aba) Collins-Sibley, 2016; 1 oral histories (1 mp4 and 4 mov video files)
- Video interview of Tobias Davis, 2016; 1 oral histories (1 mp4 and 5 mov video files)
- Text response of Kai M. Devlin, 2016; 1 oral histories (1 digital text file)
- Video interview of Robert Dunning, 2016; 1 oral histories (1 mp4 and 5 mov video files)
- Video interview of Parker Foe, 2016; 1 oral histories (1 mp4 and 5 mov video files)
- Text response of student G [pseudonym], 2016; 1 oral histories (1 digital text file)
  This interview is open for use with following restrictions on access: the narrator has requested that a pseudonym be used until January 1, 2028. A redacted version of the interview is available.
- Text response of student S [pseudonym], 2016; 1 oral histories (1 digital text file)
  This interview is open for use with following restrictions on access: the narrator has requested that a pseudonym be used. A redacted version has been made for access.
- Text response of Dinah Lensing-Sharp, 2016; 1 oral histories (1 digital text file)
- Video interview of Edsuvani Maisonet, 2016; 1 oral histories (1 mp4 and 7 mov video files)
  This interview is open for use with following restrictions on access: the narrator has requested that this interview not be made available online. Please consult with Special Collections staff to request access to this digital content. Researchers must sign an access agreement which stipulates that individuals will not be identified.
- Text response of Jess M. Montecalvo, 2016; 1 oral histories (1 digital text file)
- Video interview of Erika Nonken, 2016; 1 oral histories (1 mp4 and 1 mov video file)
- Text response of Ray Novak, 2016; 1 oral histories (1 digital text file)
  This interview is open for use with following restrictions on access: the narrator has requested that this interview not be made available online. Please consult with Special Collections staff to request access to this digital content. Researchers must sign an access agreement which stipulates that individuals will not be identified by name.
- Video interview of Izzy Owen, 2016; 1 oral histories (1 mp4 and 4 mov video files)
- Video interview of Evelyn (Evan) Parker, 2016; 1 oral histories (1 mp4 and 6 mov video files)
- Video interview of Marisa Piňero, 2016; 1 oral histories (1 mp4 and 6 mov video files)
- Video interview of Ryan Rasdall, 2016; 1 oral histories (1 mp4 and 4 mov video files)
- Video interview of Taonga (Ty) Rume, 2016; 1 oral histories (1 mp4 and 4 mov video files)
- Video interview of Cai Sherley, 2016; 1 oral histories (1 mp4 and 5 mov video files)
- Video interview of David Shlasko, 2016; 1 oral histories (1 mp4 and 5 mov video files)
- Video interview of Sophie Strauss-Jenkins, 2016; 1 oral histories (1 mp4 and 9 mov video files)
- Video interview of Beans Velocci, 2016; 1 oral histories (1 mp4 and 6 mov video files)
- Video interview of Reed Wetmore, 2016; 1 oral histories (1 mp4 and 4 mov video files)